If you search for VPN, it's the number
one app on the App Store. At this time,
we get over a million downloads a day.
Most of them are organic. Cumulatively,
we have crossed well over a billion
downloads. It's also a category where
the whole pie is increasing in size, and
our slice of the pie as a percentage is
also increasing.
>> Hello, I'm your host David Bernard, and
with me today, RevenueCat CEO Jacob
Biting. Our guest today is Tanay
Chaterjee, CEO at Super Unlimited VPN.
On the podcast, I talked with Tanay
about the product-driven growth loop
behind the number one VPN app in the
world. Why they intentionally leave
money on the table,
and how the prettiest design often loses
in their AB tests. Hey Tanay, thanks so
much for joining me on the podcast.
>> Thank you for inviting me.
>> I said joining me, but it's joining us.
Jacob, nice to have you here today as
well.
>> I'm just here David, I'm here to bring
what I can, interject, you know,
philosophy as needed, but I'm excited to
be here.
>> We had a a lively conversation before
hitting record. So, one of these days
we'll have a Sub Club After Hours
talk about life and business and
everything else. But, I wanted to kick
it off today talking about your app
Super Unlimited, and I did not know,
kind of embarrassed to say this, but I
had not heard of it until you and I met
at an App Growth Summit, and I looked it
up and was like, holy crap, this is the
number one result for VPN, and just
incredibly successful app. So, as we get
started, I wanted to give you an
opportunity to just talk a little bit
about the app and kind of the success
it's had to help people understand and
kind of frame the conversation.
>> Yeah, sure. So,
thank you for the for the kind words. If
you search for VPN, it's the number one
app on the App Store in the productivity
category before all the chat GPT kind of
clones they came in, we were always on
the top 10 along with Google. The only
other products were from Microsoft and
Google. So,
proud of what we have done over the four
five years. It's a as we talked through
the podcast we you'll you'll see it's a
lot of it is very product driven growth.
But at this time we get over a million
downloads a day. Most of them are
organic. We have received cumulatively
we have crossed well over a billion
downloads. It's also a category where
the whole pie is increasing in size and
our slice of the pie as a percentage is
also increasing in size. So, we're we
are we are we are in a good spot there.
Yes, we we have not done too much PR
marketing branding yet, but that will
that will come over time.
>> A million downloads a day, that's like
almost an unfathomable number.
I don't even know after they're still
getting a million downloads a day except
for when they like go viral or you know,
ChatGPT I'm sure had a few days like
that, maybe a few million. That is just
an insane number. And then you said most
of that is organic. So, that I wanted to
jump to that next. How did you end up at
the top result for VPN and and how do
you defend that?
>> Yeah, you know, we didn't start being on
top we didn't we didn't start trying out
to be the biggest VPN, right? We we we
basically my background just FYI is
engineering and product. Before getting
into the VPN world I was CTO at Rakuten
where we grew the company from, you
know, $30 million in revenue to billion
dollars in revenue in the US. A lot of
lessons learned around the consumer DNA
then and my given my background I think
very bottom up rather than marketing
down. Sometimes to a fault, but it has
served us well. So, you know, we
basically looked at the app started
looking at the reviews right away.
Started looking at our competitors
reviews right away to see what's missing
in our app. Not in terms of feature
functionality, but but what are people
complaining about? And we started fixing
those things. We started removing
friction. And then we started reading
the competitors reviews in in terms of
what are their challenges over there
that we can fix and resolve. We
basically built an app which was very
very high quality. I say to people
sometimes that if VPN apps are commodity
as as you know, right? It's very easy
open source codes galore in the
internet. So you can find and build a
VPN app in two weeks. The first 85% is
very easy. But the after that every 1%
is hard work. You know, how do I connect
a user who's in Poland to the best
server? What's the right server? What's
the right protocol? Uh and then there
are blocking and tackling that we'll
have to do, you know, some people will
might might block you because an airline
might might block you thinking that oh
you might be a bot. How do I give them
very very good service quality? That's
really hard work. So that's what we
focused on a lot. It's a premium app
that helps because there's no friction.
You just come in uh no login, no hard
very very heavy paywalls that are hard
to get around. You just start click on
connect and start using it, right? Our
engagement time is literally, you know,
half a second half a minute. The first
time they come in they'll have to do a
very quick setup. And after but this is
second time they come in they come in
and they click on the connect button
they go off to their Netflix or to their
browsers and all, right? And that's what
we want. We don't want people to stick
around too long. Unlike a lot of other
apps where engagement We define
engagement differently. We it's not time
spent on the app. It's actually the
intention to come back to the app.
>> And it seems like that is kind of is
kind of feeding the algorithm, right?
It's like people download the app and
then it's so easy to use. You get these
massive downloads and then that just
keeps like this perpetuating cycle. Are
there any like specific things you've
done and experimented with? Like, you
know, I know Ariel at Appfigures talks a
lot about rating velocity. You know,
have you moved the rating prompt earlier
or later and like seen moves at all in
your ASO?
>> Yeah, you know, ratings are super
important, right? But there's a time
when to ask for ratings. You can't ask
ask it too many times and too often and
at the wrong time mainly, right? We
basically ask for ratings after we've
delivered value to the user. That
multiplied by
the number of downloads, the number of
users who are coming in and using the
app and and coming back, that helps
overall. So yeah, so rating is
important, very important to us. When
people come in and look at the App
Store, not only we are number one, but
they also see two 2 million plus, you
know, very high quality ratings. That
definitely is is impactful, but we we
don't try to do too much gymnastics with
trying to get more ratings. I think they
they come organically, they come we ask
for them.
But we don't overdo it.
>> Speaking of not doing too many
gymnastics, your screenshots don't seem
especially fancy, you know, there's a
lot of trends in screenshot design now
of like bigger text and gradients and
span two screenshots with the device
image, but I looked at yours and they're
like pretty simple and straightforward.
The biggest thing I noticed was that you
use logos like HBO and Netflix and so
you're kind of telling people get get
access to these services no matter where
you are. But is that intentional? Any
any lessons for you on screenshots? Like
have they just not mattered? Have you
experimented at all with them?
>> Yeah, screenshots has been our biggest
mystery for us. So we have tried. So of
course for different regions and all we
try different screenshots, localization
and whatnot that everybody does, but our
screenshots, you know, and you've been
very polite, you know, they're they're a
bit stale. They look a little stale. And
we have tried modernizing screenshots
and I have to say 80% of the time when
we do AB tests, they lose. And it was
like, "Huh." You know, people just like
to see what they were used to seeing. So
in many cases we have gone back to the
original ones that we had. In some
cases, like I said, 20% of the cases
they do work slightly, but we have not
seen any meaningful difference when we
experimented with screenshots. We also
don't, you you because we we are, you
know, number one on the SO, we we also
don't do massive changes at the same,
you know, because it it's very risky.
So, we we we've done tweaks. We have
done new screenshots. We've done AB
tests. We've changed the colors. We've
changed what the content. We've done all
of those things in a very organized
methodical way, but most of them have
not produced results that we were
expecting. Although, you would think
that they are better and more modern and
it should be more compelling in 2026,
but it doesn't work. So, again, I think
the data is proving us wrong, which is
fine. It is It is what it the truth is,
right?
>> Yeah, I I just got done with a live
YouTube paywall race. So, we spent an
hour on the Sub Club YouTube channel
live racing paywalls. And one of the
things we talked about was like, you
sometimes, you know, quote-unquote, I
don't don't don't don't mean to be
disparaging of your screenshots. I don't
think they're ugly, but sometimes
they're like super fancy design just
doesn't perform as well. And I I don't
understand it. Like, you know, my bent
is always like make things prettier. I
don't understand why
>> It's not that the uh It's not that the
technical elite have some sort of like
uh out of step actual understanding of
what people want or like. No, it's not
that. It's that people have no taste,
David.
>> People have no taste.
Well, next I wanted to dig into SEO cuz
it's something I I've I've had so many
people I mean, maybe less so the last
year. Like, now it's more about LLM
optimization, but so many people over
the years have asked about breaking into
SEO. And I know it's something a project
y'all worked on. What are your lessons
from there? And then to tack on to that,
have you seen the work you did do in SEO
start to pay off in showing up in LLM
responses?
>> Let me go back a little bit. So, till
beginning of last year, we were only a
mobile app. We were just a one-page site
because there was no need for it. So,
right? So, last year, late last year, we
launched our Windows product. And it to
get ready for that, uh we had to build
start building a web presence, right?
SEO takes time, right? So, we said, "In
2025, where do we start?" So, what we
did was we started with programmatic
content. So, we worked with this company
called Daydream. The founder I knew the
founder from before. He had actually
worked in the VPN space before, so he
already knew the domain. So, I said,
"Okay, let's let's help help me out."
So, yeah, so we started seeing results
there, but the conversion was still not
that great. So, we it's still a work in
progress for us. It's still early. I'm
not an expert there. I know SEO in
general has suffered. Every consumer
company that's relies on the web traffic
is suffering a little bit. Both SEO is
down a little bit because, you know, the
first results that you see are Gemini
and whatnot in Google, as well as uh
even paid search marketing is is less
effective because the the real estate is
gone. Part of the real estate for the
first page is gone because Gemini takes
it over. So, a lot of people are
struggling. So, I don't think we we will
spend time on SEO, but we won't over
index on SEO. I think one of the our
biggest channels for growth, even to
send them to make them start using
Windows, is through our big mobile user
base, right? So, we'll spend a lot of
time on product marketing within mobile.
SEO, we know will it'll take time. We
are still working on it. We have content
people. We have SEO people, but we are
that's not the top channel for us.
>> It is funny because I read their case
study about this and it's doing like
1,600 app downloads per month, which for
at your scale, that's just such peanuts.
But for a lot of apps, that would be a
pretty meaningful improvement to
downloads. So, it's it's all about scale
there. But I did want to follow up with
that last point about LLMs. Have you
found that because of the SEO efforts
that you've put in, have you started
showing up higher or what's your your
LLM I I forget what it What's Either of
you know the What's the LLM term for
SEO?
>> GEO, right? Generative engine
optimization. It's It used to be like
LEO, or but that's lower orbit, so it's
like
>> I You know, I was It's interesting you
asked. I was looking at Google Analytics
the other day on for our web. There is
traffic coming in. There are downloads
coming in from there. It's not in the
top five channels, but it is coming. So,
it's it's a good sign that we are
starting to get more visibility.
>> interesting. I think it's we see so much
higher on the like dev tool side, but it
makes sense. I feel like choosing a VPN
is a Like you know exactly what you're
going for at that point, you know,
versus like I just my naivety about the
VPN market, but it's like I don't I
don't suppose people are being like,
"How do I tunnel my tra- You know what I
mean?" They know they need a VPN cuz
somebody told them like if you want to
do this, you need a VPN, right? And so
they should search those three letters.
>> Yeah, and also I would say there are
bigger VPN players out there, not in
bigger in terms of downloads, but there
are, you know, a couple you know, few
VPN players who are premium only, while
we are freemium. So, their downloads are
smaller, but their LTVs are much bigger.
And they came in from the desktop side
of things. And they've spent years
focusing on SEO. So, if you're looking
for, "Oh, you know, I'm in Bolivia and
where do I watch the Winter Olympics
right now?" I'm I bet you that you'll
find a website from them.
>> Even on consumer, cuz I was like I say,
VPN market's really funny cuz things
like Tailscale and Citrix are like also
in the VPN market, but don't feel like
direct competitors to you, right? No.
>> Some of them are, you know, more more
catering to the B2B to C side side,
right? And we are we are purely consumer
play, yeah.
>> I did want to dive a little deeper into
the freemium side of things, cuz it does
seem like this is a big part of your
growth engine is having that freemium
tier, which allows you to get so many
downloads and so many ratings, which
then gets more downloads. How have you
balanced the monetization? And then as a
VPN, how do you manage costs for those
free users?
>> Our free to paid conversion is quite
low, and I'm okay with it because we
have focused on the top of the funnel a
lot. I There are a lot of companies,
smaller competitors in the premium
world, who would try to be get more
aggressive in monetization, and I think
that's not our philosophy, right? We
want to give you a very, very, very,
very good quality free product. And the
reason it's low, not because the product
sucks, is because our free version is
that good. So, there are you don't want
to throttle or take things away from the
free version like
like
There's a reason we have the word
unlimited in our name, where if if you
want to come and you can't pay, that's
that's fine, you know, you probably just
will have to watch an ad or two, and
then you can use it unlimited. We have,
you know, dozens and dozens of countries
and cities that you can connect to just
fine. I would rather give people more
value before asking them for more money,
because So, it's a denominator game,
right? So, part of the reason you you
also alluded to before that you you
know, your most of the users are
organic. Partly because we are it's a
numbers game for us. Our LTV, because
it's premium, because of a big majority
of the users are are premium, our LTV is
not that high. We can't compete with
Spotifys of the world, where, you know,
where their LTV and and retention is
amazingly high. But we are adding a lot
more now. Talking about adding more
value, we we are we are adding Windows,
so not only you can protect your mobile
phone, but you can protect all your all
of your devices, Windows,
Mac, mobile phones across the family. We
talked about, you know, adding a second
phone number app, so we can throw it in
the bundle. I think that's what That's
where we're going. But the main thing is
our top of the funnel is our superpower.
Don't mess with it. Give people a
fantastic free VPN experience.
>> So, do you manage the ad revenue to
break even on the free users, or do you
even lose a little money on the free
users? And and how do you make money on
ads? Are there Are they full-screen
interstitials? Do those pay reasonably
well? Like
>> Do they get it injected into your web
pages?
>> No, no. So, you know, it's limited,
right? So, I mentioned our our average
engagement time is 30 seconds on the app
or less. So, you don't have much of a
window to show an ad. So, you're to your
point, yes, we have interstitials and we
have full-screen ads and we have some
native banners and all, but we don't try
to optimize it for traffic necessarily.
Some countries, you know, high rev
countries, US, Western Europe and all,
you know, they're profitable and in some
in some cases, you know, the match rates
are low, the CPMs are very low. It's
totally okay with us. So, I came from
the e-commerce world, right? We used to
get spikes on Valentine's Day and, you
know, Mother's Day and Black Friday and
Cyber Monday. Our spikes usually happen
because of geopolitical issues. So, I'll
give you an example, like I think was it
it was last year, Turkey banned
Instagram for 11 days and we got 15
million downloads in 4 days. And the I
mean, if you think of Turkey's
population, it's 85 million. And, you
know, if you think of 15 million
downloads and think of the internet
population using it, it's probably 30 to
40%, right? So, do we make that much
money in Turkey? Probably not. I mean,
there are countries where there are more
issues that are poorer, Myanmar, for
example, right? They having a civil war,
but we just think it's the right thing
to do. People should have access to
information. People should access to
free information. Uh they should not be
constrained by just propaganda. So, we
just provide service uh even if we lose
money. As long as yes, we are running a
business, we but we we are not trying to
over-optimize this, right?
>> Are you on ads? Do you defer showing ads
until like you've determined somebody's
like not a likely purchaser? Do you have
any orchestration between like showing
ads versus not and stuff like that or or
are you thinking about it that
granularly yet?
>> For the first download, if you just
installed it, we don't show an ad right
away, right?
>> So, yes, I guess is the answer. It's
like you do some sort of smart and be
like, okay, we're going to defer to see
if this person's going to they might
convert right away and we don't want to
degrade the experience.
>> It's not just for conversion. It's also,
you know, we want them to see the value
of the app, right? So, even the paywalls
are not very hard. There's a big X sign
where you can cancel out very easily.
So, we we're not trying to over monetize
it. Just the main goal is come and use
the product.
>> Yeah, I guess like becoming their VPN
app is probably more important than
monetizing on that.
>> Money will come. Money will come, right?
Everything else will it will come.
>> It sounds like part of how you manage
this is just to keep costs really low so
that you're not bleeding out by serving
all of these freemium users. Any any
lessons there about just keeping costs
>> This is my naivete on on VPNs, but but
you all have to maintain that tunneling
infrastructure, right? Or do you rent
that out from somebody?
>> No, we we maintain it. Yeah, we spend
So, David, you're right. Managing the
cost is key, but not at the cost of
service quality. So, every data packet
for a VPN goes through our servers,
right? So, if people in Turkey or you
know, some of the lower revenue
countries, if they're using it,
sometimes you lose out, too. And it's
okay. It's it's okay with us. What we
can control a little more or what we
want to control is marketing costs,
right? That's why we we spend money in
marketing and we will continue spending
more, but that's where we can control
things. We won't make any compromises on
service quality.
>> So, then I mean, you're business, how do
you make money?
Like what what are the features that you
put behind the paywall? Like how do you
entice people to actually subscribe when
you do provide such a fantastic freemium
product?
>> The extra value that we can provide with
with a paid product is of course no ads,
top tier customer support, but also a
lot more locations and access to higher
10G servers and whatnot, right? But now,
starting late last year, multi-platform,
where, you know, once you subscribe, you
can use the VPN for all the platforms.
So, we're upping the value game. That's
how we make money. We By the way, we're
growing very nicely. We're very
profitable. The investors are not
pushing me otherwise, so it's a good
position to be in.
>> Yeah, what an incredible position to be
in. I mean, the the deeper we get into
this conversation, it sounds like there
is so much dry powder with a billion
downloads and so such a huge premium
base that as you do find secondary
product market fit, find new features to
add, things like that, you've got so
much dry powder to really build the
business over time.
>> Yeah, yeah, we we looking at long-term,
right? Because because we are unlike
some of the other VPN companies that are
that are for desktop first, some of the
bigger competitors that we have. We are
mobile first, right? And
so one of the apps we recently launched
and we are cleaning it up and all before
bundling it or promoting it heavy
heavily is this eSIM app. So think of
think of this, right? So a lot of VPN
user that we have, think of the cohorts,
right? There's a lot of people who are
travelers. They just travel to Europe,
but they cannot access their favorite
content or they cannot access their bank
and all, right? Or immigrants that want
to watch a show, like a Korean immigrant
in the US, they wanted to watch a Korean
show and whatnot. So there's a lot of
access-based issues that happen once you
cross the borders, right? We think eSIM
is a fantastic market and intersects
very well with our user base, right?
Just last year, 500 million people
traveled to Europe. If you think of it,
it's a very big part of the affluent
global population who can afford to
travel to Europe. Are there a lot of
these people who are using our VPN
products? Yes. Do they need eSIMs? Yes.
>> I went to those in Europe last week and
I used for the first time I did it and
like it's I mean, compared to like the
pay $10 a day, get ripped off, slow
access, it was pretty good. I paid $20
for the whole week. I had like first
party a pretty decent access. It wasn't
perfect, but it was like pretty decent
and I didn't have to worry about and it
like you didn't have to you don't have
to go to a a shady shop and get a card
to slide into your phone. It's like it's
it's pretty cool and I'll tell you I
think there's opportunity in the market
because the the two like I I to use the
names you've heard of. The first one
like their website didn't even work on
mobile. It's so bad. Which I was like,
seems like this should probably work. I
think it failed because I was on my
phone on bad service, which I'm like,
pretty sure that's a test case you
should probably have nailed. It's like
your website shouldn't require
JavaScript and be like so crazy.
Uh but anyway, I think I mean, I buy it.
I think that's a great strategic
direction.
>> Think of other values. So, we have this
massive customer base. What else will
they value? It's not what else can I
sell to them, right? I don't even need
to sell, right? Here's what we have, you
know, do you want to use it? And they're
privacy conscious users, they're access
conscious users. I think there's a with
a large denominator, even a small change
in the in the multiple of conversions
will help a lot.
>> Your your denominator at a billion
downloads
or is the magnitude larger than most
denominators in the subscription app
space?
>> I mean, it's a tough challenge. I mean,
it's a a blessing and a curse cuz once
you're at those mega num- I mean, I
guess if you're playing at like a like a
flywheel game, right? Where you're
taking the current volume and you're
adding new things. Like that's fun,
right? I think once you get to that
scale, it's kind of can be kind of
demoralizing cuz you're like, well,
there's just no more people.
You know? Like
>> That's the part of it. The downside of
being the number one is where will the
future growth come from for the for the
top of the funnel, right?
>> Return on At the end of the day, it's
return on capital, right? Like where's
it coming from? You know?
>> It's a it's a very first world problem
to have, but it is a problem
nevertheless.
>> So, you mentioned earlier, we you know,
we focused a lot on the organic side of
things, but you mentioned that you do do
some marketing and it's something that
it sounds like you're maybe you're
looking to do more of so more people are
aware of it.
>> to say if you start selling eSIMs,
you're going to need to get to know some
ad buyers in airports, you know? Like
it's a very like on prem advertising.
>> We are also learning, right? So, Ethan
was like, okay, you know, we have so
many users. Just join an ad. Let's see
how it goes. And unless people are
traveling, there's no intent. I mean,
why would you buy an eSIM right now,
right? So, it's like, okay, good to
know. I mean, come summer or before
summer, came your presence promotions at
the right time. Not every phone is eSIM
compatible either, right? Do we again,
do we not bombard people with an eSIM
ad? Just be very deliberate about who we
want to show it to, who will actually
get value out of it, right? So, the ads
is another one of those things you
talked about ads, right? I would rather
leave 10% money on the table rather than
bombard people with that. There's a lot
of trust that you destroy with overdoing
monetization.
>> And back to like um growth side of
things, what have you done in paid
marketing or has it almost been
completely organic?
>> Well, Apple and Google, you know, it's
uh for for search ads, yeah. Yeah, yeah.
>> Have you found the brand defense
especially important or or like what
wins have you found on search ads when
you're already the number one result?
>> Well, number one result on VPN, right?
There are other keywords in there, too.
Sometimes you also do it for brand
defense, like you mentioned. There are
other keywords, you know, we focus on
specific keywords, specific markets
where we where we spend dollars on and
we look into the ROAS very carefully and
you can't go beyond a certain amount. We
also see sometimes these some of these
ads will cannibalize our organic
channels anyway, so there's always that
risk, but it's okay, right? So, so we
we're trying to manage it carefully.
>> It's fascinating your scale that you do
spend on that and then philosophically
you're still trying to get a return on
ad spend. You're still like penciling it
out versus just like trying to be
everywhere because you already are
everywhere with that number one
placement, so
>> Five years ago, we were not number one
everywhere, right? We were probably
number one in a couple of locations in
iOS. Now, we we track 71 countries and
right now for the VPN keyword, we are
number one in 67 of those, right? And
number two in in the rest. In Android,
we are not as successful. We are number
one in the US right now. We are in the
top five or top 10 almost everywhere,
but it's not that we are number one
everywhere, right? So, we do see that as
an opportunity. It's like glass half
full or glass half empty, right? Okay,
where can I use some extra marketing
push to kind of get up there because I
think the brand definitely helps.
>> I wanted to transition and talk about
some of your product-driven approach to
growth. And one of the things I found
fascinating was that you put your
support team inside the product team.
How do How does that work?
>> The head of support reports to the head
of product. I want a mirror in front of
the product team right there, right?
It's not Our growth comes from product
decisions and not just from marketing
campaigns. Sometimes we know that what
are people struggling with? What's not
clear? What are people asking about over
and over? So, that could be a UX issue,
that could be a communication issue, or
an education issue, or an or onboarding
issue. Service quality. Ah, you know,
I'm in Uganda and I'm starting to see a
lot of service quality tickets, you
know, product should know first right
away. I have been at companies where,
you know, product and support was a
totally separate organization and
support will talk do a do a talk once a
month and show their KPIs and how many
tickets they've solved. It's fine,
right? But, the pace at which the
feedback loop goes into the product side
of the engineering side is a lot less.
So, we because we are so focused and
anal about product quality, we wanted
the the support team inside the product
team itself.
>> I mean, we we essentially, not exactly,
have that at RevenueCat, but support has
been an engineering attachments at
RevenueCat since day one and it's like
both for both for cultural reasons cuz
like it's engineers asking most of our
questions, so it makes sense. Um, talent
reasons, but I just think that like it's
same with like QA. Like I think QA, I
don't know how if you guys are doing it
or anyway special, but when I got into
the industry, it was very normal for QA
to be in the other building kind of
situation, you know?
And like I think now QA teams don't
really exist cuz it's all been merged.
You have junior engineers, right? You
have like people on the team, and maybe
it's support sometimes. Like that's
kind of our closest thing to a QA team.
It's like the support engineers like
involved in the product development. Um
and it seems to work so much better.
>> The fewer dependencies you have, the
better. And And if you have a
dependencies, it cannot be the next
building over, right? You should be able
to
>> Well, we don't buildings anymore, so we
solved that problem.
>> Right. Right.
>> Everybody's in another building
in 2026.
>> Mentally you're in another building,
right? Yes.
>> You mentioned earlier in the podcast,
and it was something again that stood
out to me about your kind of philosophy
is the bottoms-up, not marketing down.
Any other top lessons there, or anything
else you wanted to share about that
approach to product development and
marketing?
>> For us, for our domain, service quality
is massive. Because there are always a
lot of corner cases, you know, I could
be I think about it, right? You have a
phone, 3G network in Nepal, and you're
on Wi-Fi in your hotel, and then you
walked out in an elevator, for some time
it disconnected, and then you are on a
3G line or a 4G line, and then something
else happened. You're in a bus, you're
traveling, you you switch from one tower
to the other tower. VPN in particular,
as opposed to most of the other
tech world, where you know, it's just
quick request and response. It's a very
long-lived connection, right? So,
technically there are a lot of
challenges that come with that. And
people are our customers are on the
move. So, a lot of focus on that.
>> I mean, getting all the edge cases
right. Like it is the whole product. The
last 10% is the whole product, probably.
It's kind of I think you said something
to that effect in the beginning, but I
think that's what, you know, sometimes
differentiates great products and and
commodities, right? Is like do they do
they just always work? Um versus like
sometimes maybe work.
>> So, it's not just engineering, right?
It's the operational discipline. That
That is important. Meaning like reacting
to all the issues, like actually taking
the time and investing in finding them.
Anticipating, reacting. I mean, our our
QA guy actually walked with his phone to
his into inside an elevator, down. He
had a debug build so he could see all
the logs at at that time, and he
did the whole thing a few times. So,
that's how, you know, that's how you get
better.
>> This is just a I mean, a mobile thing. I
think in a lot of app developers,
especially where we're now we're seeing
like so many app developers coming into
the market. And like you kind of always
assume good Wi-Fi, beefy connections,
whatever. Which is a
rarity, right? Or certainly it's not
going to like make your app great, you
know? Like you you could be okay, but
like if it's like I was using a fairly
new app. I won't I won't name names, but
like you've heard of it, and um it's in
the AI category. And like their offline
stuff just like didn't work for me. Like
it like I downloaded it, and then I got
offline and opened it up on the plane,
and like I just got a login screen. And
I was like, I mean, I I can see that's
like a second-order case, right? Um and
maybe that's forgivable for a first year
app or whatever. But in mobile, like you
have to nail that. You have to nail the
offline case, the online case, the
middle in case, the changing countries
case, right? But I was kind of
wondering, you know, again it goes back
to like VPN being a commodity.
Like what brands could potentially just
attach a brand to it, you know, cuz
sometimes like commodities just like
Coca-Cola, it's the brand, right? You're
not it's the sugar water, whatever, but
it's mostly the brand you're buying. So,
it's like are there brands that could
just buy them being the brand they are?
Like DuckDuckGo's maybe a good example.
They're not they're even very niche.
It might be like Symantec or something
like that, but I think that's like a
20-year-old brand now. I don't think
that or like whatever that doesn't
really have the cachet that it maybe
used to. But are there like are there
like big brands like that? Or like and
they just are not investing at the level
that you are on the product?
>> No, they are they are bigger brands. And
without naming names, you know, there
are bigger brands and bigger companies,
and they come more from the desktop side
in the VPN space. And this
>> But that's that's a different problem,
right? Like a desktop, you know, on the
bus, you know what I mean? You're not
like So is that your Is it your Is this
just them by them not being mobile
first?
You By being mobile first, you can you
can just have an advantage because
>> We have an advantage. Desktop people pay
more.
>> Oh, sure. Sure. Well, it's a trade-off,
right? It's like scale scale low LTV,
you know, but but but there's a niche
there, right?
>> You have to go and tackle and understand
that market a lot more, right? The users
are different, right? The mobile user
case I just explained, right? They're a
little less more forgiving because they
do experience these issues when when
walking
>> Right. Right. I'm not using this to
connect to my company's VPN, right? So
it's it's different.
>> Desktop users are less forgiving. Yes,
the tech technical challenges are not
that the person is moving and shifting
to 3G. You can assume that the the
connection is strong,
but, you know, if let's say if they're
gaming, the reaction time needs to be
very fast. Otherwise,
you cannot you cannot have any latency
in in in gaming, right?
>> I was going to say I think that would be
the only time I've used Well, except for
work. I like a desktop VPN was like when
I was trying to do LAN games with people
and it was just easier to to have a
virtual LAN that you're on.
>> So the the challenges are different,
right? Bandwidth is very high, right? If
you they're downloading big content or
streaming in 4G and all, you need to
make sure the bandwidth is top tier. The
latency is as low as possible.
Everything is the same.
>> And those are all things you control cuz
it's like you have the edge nodes, you
have the relays, like that's all
infrastructure you have to monitor and
and and pay attention to.
>> We control it, but it's still a
good engineering problem, right? Because
you are connected to some servers for a
very long time, for hours in many cases.
So if
the load balancing happens in a very
different way.
>> I mean, this is maybe too much This is
off of the sub club beat, but like is it
Can you just host that You guys just run
that in a like a standard cloud
infrastructure or do you need like
specialized infrastructure?
>> No. No. No. We have So our I'm getting a
bit geeky with you right now, but
>> It's great. We can edit it out. This is
just for us.
>> All right. Our control plane is in the
cloud in the standard well-known cloud
infrastructures. Our data plane is not
because we lose our shirts because the
bandwidth cost
>> Yeah, cuz it's not designed for just
tunneling tons of traffic.
>> for that. So, our
>> to go to like a layer lower to rent that
or
>> Yeah, where we have control, we get bare
metal machines, we control it, we we
wipe it out, and
>> Oh, okay. So, you actually Yeah, that
that that's very interesting. Which is
also another advantage versus like any
other David was talking about like kind
of cost inputs, right? Like when you
have that scale, you can afford to make
the investment to control your data
plane get way better rates, and that
allows you to have like a different
retail economics than than somebody who
might have to rent it all from AWS and
pay ingress egress or whatever.
>> Yeah, yeah. So, so those cost
optimizations we do. Not We don't do
cost optimizations that'll affect
service quality. That's the last thing
we will touch. We won't touch it ever.
>> This is great Sub Club content. I know
what you're talking about, Jacob. We got
a little nerdy there about control
planes and data packets, but but it it
is super meaningful.
>> People on this podcast make software
still, I think. That's you know what I
mean? This is part of the how the
sausage is made.
>> And it's super meaningful to the
business to build those cost advantages.
And then as subscription app businesses,
this is part of what you have to be
figuring out. And like, you know, I
mean, even in this conversation, I'm
thinking about my dinky weather app, and
part of the reason I don't have a
freemium tier is because our data is
really expensive.
>> David, invest in weather stations. You
need a weather station in every place on
the earth.
>> Well, now what a what a lot of apps do
for for weather is they do actually just
use the National Weather Service data,
which is generally pretty good, and it's
free, and we can like, you know, there
there are ways that we can control our
costs so that we could offer a freemium
experience to users. So, that it's it's
inspiring me to me to to go this deep
because I I think a lot of people should
be thinking along these lines.
>> Revenue Cats had a free experience, and
and we designed it to be supportable
from the beginning. Like all of our cost
scaling is such that like if if
somebody's not paying if a user end end
users not paying it doesn't really cost
us much to support and that takes design
choices, right? Like there's ways we
could have designed it that wouldn't
have been that way.
>> And that's allowed us to maintain this
really nice freemium tier.
>> No, but you open up the funnel right
there, right? 10x and it has to be still
it has to provide meaningful value,
right?
>> Yeah, but then the value is we can give
the product away for free if you're
small, right? And just say like hey,
just use it. Don't worry about it. We'll
get you later. Don't worry about it, you
know.
>> In the era of insane inference costs,
this is a very important as well. It's
like
>> Yeah, yeah. I mean every app that's AI
driven is kind of you know, really
having to think about this stuff
heavily.
>> You know, can you run an open source
model? But but I think to Nagesh you
keep hammering on don't sacrifice
service quality. I think that is one of
the challenges currently is that the
leading model providers like OpenAI and
Anthropic and Google have set the bar so
high from what kind of a response you
could get that a lot of people got super
excited about Apple's on device AI stuff
and my pushback the whole time was like
people just expect so much out of AI and
you're not going to get that from a
local model. And it's going to be a
while and then as as soon as the local
models get better, the leading models
will get even better. And so but there
are opportunities cut costs by using
open source models, by using different
hosting and things like that. But if you
do that at the expense of service
quality, if your product degrades
because you're trying to cut costs,
that's not a good experience.
>> this is this is really prescient in the
the AI moment for all these apps that
are shipping AI features too. It's like
you know, it's it's a it's also
important to think about cuz I I assume
you all did not have your data plane in
house on day one, right?
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah. So day one you don't
build for Google scale or for our scale,
right?
>> Fastest. It's all about the fastest,
>> You need to be the fastest. Get to
market fastest. You can optimize the
cost later.
>> Exactly. And then that's what I was
going to suggest is like have a path.
Just understand that you can and it's
like when we're we're building AI stuff
internally at RevenueCat right now, it's
like don't worry about it. We'll we'll
spend the big It's going to be
expensive. It's going to be a loss
leader or whatever. Two things are going
to happen. The models are going to get
cheaper in 6 months, 12 months, and then
we're also going to get smarter about
using them. So, like, the the costs are
not going to go up from here, right? So,
the marginal costs at least.
>> Time to market is huge. The you know,
initially your your volume won't be that
big. If the volume If the volume gets
bigger, it's the good problem to have.
>> this is always a I love this is like a
classic like early entrepreneur mistake
when they're like, you over obsess about
I'm going to lose my shirt or like
whatever. It's like, this is not going
to be a problem. If it is a problem,
it's a good problem, right? And like, I
don't think any Also, I don't think AWS
has taken anybody's house yet for not
paying a bill, so like, typically
>> Don't optimize too early. Find a product
market fit, you know, grow the funnel,
and there's so many levers that you can
pull for for cost without sacrificing
service quality.
>> Yeah, I mean, I just love the philosophy
of like, focus on the product. I mean,
this is RevenueCat MO is customer
obsession. Just talk to a customer, see
what they want. That's our only guiding
principle is like, talk to them and see
what's broken, and then apply our gifts
to try to to serve them, and you know,
ultimately creating surplus value,
right? Which then you mentioned the
money will come, and it will. Like, if
you create surplus value, the actually
capture part can is kind of the the easy
part, right? If there's so much surplus
value created, you'll find a way to like
to share in that. And there's
optimizations. You can 1 2 X 5 X that
one way or the other, but like, unless
you focus on the first thing, which is
value creation, none of the rest is
going to matter.
>> So, in those early days, well, actually,
let's let's even step back. So, my
understanding, correct me if I'm wrong,
Super Unlimited was spun out of Rakuten.
How did that all happen? And then And
then we can tie it into like the early
days where you were just using, you
know, off-the-shelf cloud hardware. And
then when When did it start making sense
to to build out your own infrastructure?
>> Yeah, Super Unlimited was spun out, but
not from Rakuten. So, I had left
Rakuten. I joined this company at that
time that was called AnchorFree, and we
used We had a few VPN products. You can
look it up. But during while I was
there, we had bought this product called
VP VPN Super Unlimited Proxy. Good
enough product, nothing like what it is
right now. And I was there as I was
running engineering at that that
company. I was their CTO. And then when
Anchorfree was bought by a larger
company, I decided to step away. My
investors said, "Hey, Tanel, you don't
go anywhere. Here's the product that we
bought. Can you run it? Let's let's just
try to grow it." It sounds fun.
Let's try it out, right? I had managed
engineering
I'm an engineer I've done engineering
and then managed engineering all my
life. This was something interesting.
I'm like, "What do I have to lose? Let's
try it out." And yeah, so I was not the
founder of the product. It came from
somewhere, but we grew it substantially
over the last 5 years. So, 5 years ago,
beginning of January in 2021,
we spun off Super Unlimited as its own
company.
>> That's a crazy story. From app
acquisition to spun out to the top VPN
app with a billion downloads. That's
crazy. So So, what point in that in that
story early on you were just on
commodity hardware? When did things
start picking up? What was the
inflection point? What happened that
that really started move the needle? And
then when did you start building out
your own infrastructure?
>> It was not like one golden moment where
everything changed, right? It was a lot
of things along the way. Unfortunately,
there was no one silver bullet. But you
know, we looked in like I said, we
looked into
reviews. What's keeping us away from
being the number one product? A lot of
it came back to service quality for us.
So, we spent a lot of time on service
quality. And that's
thankfully that's my that's my DNA and
that's how I think, too. We started
building a team. We started focusing on
service quality. We started some basic
things about ASO, you know,
localizations and and whatnot. But
mainly service quality. And then things
started going up. In the last 5 years,
as you know, a lot of geopolitical
things also happened, right? Where
suddenly we'll get a massive spike. So,
as we were starting to go up, we will
see a massive spike from country A
versus country B. And what happens is
once the spike is gone, you hit a new
normal at at a higher level. So, you
know, so some of those things also And
we were like I said, in many cases we
were not making money, we were we were
losing money. There are many countries
right now in the this world where we
lose a lot of money, but it's totally
okay with us. That was totally okay with
us even then, right? We
"Okay, let's let's build a product that
everybody wants to use and and we are
proud of." And that flywheel took
effect. We kept in improving service
quality. We spent some time on the SO,
you know, those things we did, but I'm
sure there are companies that are doing
a much better job than us on that one.
But the thing that I'm is not important,
it's important and we we spent some time
on it. Did we do the best we could? At
that point, yes. Are there better ways
to do it? I'm 100% sure, yes, right? So,
most of it was product. Give give the
service to anybody who needs it. Don't
over index on monetization. Money will
come. All those things that we talked
about earlier, right? So, and slowly and
surely it went up. Talking about
ratings, right? So, we also broke down
the ratings by different countries, for
example, right? Okay, you know, this
country, the ratings are quite a bit
lower than US, let's say, right? Why is
that? So, so understanding and digging
into the details helped us a lot.
>> One thing I've learned is from this is
that VPNs are good like inverse a hedge
against world order. So, like
if Ray Dalio's right, everything's
breaking down, I should just buy VPN
stocks cuz like apparently that's a good
Yeah, a good hedge.
>> So, what we did was we expanded, we
added lot lot of new vendors, we
upgraded our vendors.
>> I mean, also you I imagine you have to
internationalize too at some point. Like
you need nodes in like every country for
like good latency and stuff like this.
>> So, we have tens of thousands of servers
in dozens of countries right now, yeah.
Coming back, we We use cloud for spikes,
right? The downside of bare metal is it
cannot handle surges that well, right?
We can add a little extra capacity, but
think of the turkey kind of a situation
where we added I mean, we were
practically serving Turkish population.
>> solution to the spike problem, right?
You either are way over provisioned and
you're losing your shirt or like you and
you can't react like fast even even if
it's a a wave that takes days, it's like
takes time to provision.
>> So then you use cloud providers for
surges, right?
>> Soak up this the excess, right?
>> Soak up the excess very quickly. Bare
metal you have to order it and they take
a week for them to deliver and nobody
has 500 servers sitting around, right?
Yeah.
>> Exactly. Well, somebody has to, right?
So it's just like how it's a it's a
financial operation problem to see who
holds that.
Which is like going back to the thing
David about like, you know, building
your own weather parsing or running your
own local models. It's like when you add
in all the costs of like the hardware
sitting there and not being used, you
know, like at least if you're buying
tokens from Anthropic or whoever, like
you know, they're fully utilizing their
hardware, right? So there's a much
higher utilization, right? So you you
you might be surprised that like your
amortized costs aren't that different.
>> Yeah, now if you're building a company
or a mobile app which is not a VPN, just
go with cloud, right? I mean, and prove
fastest way do it and then optimize
later.
>> Everything's portable, too. The nice
thing about, you know, TCP/IP is
standard. You can
you can do it on anything.
What What are the other things I did
want to dig into was the 80/20 rule.
Like I know that's part of your
philosophy, but you've also talked again
and again about service quality. Like
how do you not over perfect everything
and still actually ship? How do you
balance and decide what's good enough
when your North Star is service quality?
>> We cannot compromise on privacy or trust
and we don't compromise on service
quality. What we can compromise on is
features. So I'll give you an example.
The algorithm itself for a VPN user
which server to connect to, which
protocol to use, is very complex, right?
And the algorithm that you need or the
the rules that you need to connect you
in the US will be very different from
somebody who's connecting from, let's
say, Saudi Arabia, right? We have built
a lot of domain expertise to understand
what we need to do for which country,
right? We were building this algorithm
and it would have taken months and
months to build it right. So, we said,
"Okay, you know what? Do we have this
algorithm, what we think is right for
these five countries? Let's just launch
it." So, we use feature flags and we
used it just for those five countries
and for the rest we can build over time.
We could be wrong. We could have been
wrong, right? In which case we have to
iterate on it and and got it right. We
we could have introduced some bugs. So,
iterate it right now and get it right.
So, that's how we do it, right? We we
will do it in smaller chunks rather than
build a big massive Taj Mahal and launch
it. All right. Well, as we're wrapping
up, there's three questions I now ask
every guest. So, let's start with what
is the biggest win of the last year? An
experiment that, like, you know,
increased revenue 20%
anything like that, a new paywall. What
was the biggest win of the last year?
It's less about an experiment, it's more
about us building and launching our
Windows product. As I mentioned, it's a
first world problem, but the downside of
being number one is where's the new
growth coming from? Where's the forward
looking growth coming from? And this is
what we are betting on. This is one one
of the big things that we are betting on
that will drive us future growth. We are
already starting to see a lot of takers.
People are coming in onto our website
and buying it directly with the
surprise. Like, our website was didn't
even exist. So, our brand is known. We
have to start doing a lot more product
marketing this year. So, building a
product that we we are happy about, that
we are proud of, is great. It took more
time because we had a product we were
not very happy with some of the service
quality issues. I'm sure there's still
issues that we will find, but but but
finally it was at a place where where we
are very happy about. We launched it and
we are very excited about us showcasing
it to our users for future for our
forward-looking growth.
>> I don't think many companies in 2026
would say that their biggest win was
launching on Windows.
But that's a pretty cool
>> Don't sleep on Windows, David. Don't
sleep on Redmond. It's It's It's a lot
of companies' famous last mistake, you
know.
>> All right. And then how about what was
the biggest fail of the year? Experiment
that went off the rails.
>> Not shipping on Windows soon enough.
Sorry.
>> I think not a big one, but a lot of
little ones, right? Like
we talked about the the the screenshot
exper- our we're working towards on
improving our design and UI. It's a bit
stale still. It has improved a lot over
the last in the last 12 months.
Sometimes, as we talked about, right? We
we tried new ways of screens. 80% of
them failed because people didn't like
it. The previous screens were much
better. We just thought, you know, these
designs are, you know, not that great,
but it's what people like. So, that's
that's what I would say. If it's the
biggest, I don't know, but it's one of
the things that surprised us.
And lessons learned.
>> Oh, that's great. That counts. Biggest
fail was changing your screenshots to a
prettier design.
Again, not a failure you'd expect.
>> Never change anything. That's kind of I
>> And then the last question is growth
would be easier if
>> if we figured out how to bundle our
offerings without friction, right? We
won't get it So, we have Windows now. We
have We We just launched as Eastern
product. We We are acquiring and almost
at the at the end of acquiring a second
phone number. Great products. How do we
bundle? What kind of message do we do?
How do I reduce friction in terms of,
you know, people using the other
products, too? Who do I target? How do I
target? So, I think there's a lot of
things and a lot of experiments we will
run. We won't get it right the first
time 100%, but I think there's
definitely a big cohort of users who
want to use these other products. We
have to We have to get the answers right
there. So, yeah, it'll be easier after
we fail a few times.
>> All right. Well, as we wrap up, anything
you wanted to share with our audience,
any job postings you want to shout out,
or anything our audience can do for you?
>> There are a lot of job postings. All of
them are in Asia or Europe. Uh so
>> We we have a big audience around the
world, so yeah.
>> Because our product and engineering
teams are mainly in Asia and Europe, so
that's why we we want it there. We are
looking for an eSIM product manager. We
are looking for a growth product
manager, growth manager, or a director.
eSIM product manager, ideally somebody
who's worked worked in the eSIM space.
We are always looking for engineers and
QA people. There are at least 15 job
postings. I don't remember all of them
right now, but if you have any if you
are excited about this, if you are in
Asia or Europe, please send an email to
jobs@superlimited.com,
and I promise you I will personally take
a look.
>> Awesome. Thanks so much for joining us,
Tanuj. This was a a really fun
conversation, a lot of great insights.
>> Nice to talk to you. Thanks, Jacob. Take
care, David.
>> Thanks so much for listening.
If you have a minute, please leave a
review in your favorite podcast player.
You can also stop by chat.subclub.com
to join our private community.